Pooja Agarwal, Frontend Developer

■ poojaagarwal367@gmail.com • apooja.dev □ (+91)9026343013 • github.com/apooja21

SUMMARY

Experienced and motivated Frontend Developer with 2+ years of combined experience in software development, encompassing both testing and frontend development roles. Possesses a strong foundation in core web technologies (HTML, CSS, JavaScript) and modern frameworks (React, Typescript), coupled with backend capabilities in Node.js, MongoDB, and Express.js. Demonstrates adaptability and a passion for learning, evidenced by successful transition from test engineering to frontend development and continuous self-improvement during a career break through freelance projects and skill acquisition in React, Typescript, and backend technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Career Break April 2022 - Present

- Took a career break to focus on family caregiving.
- · Focused on developing frontend development skills to transition from software testing.
- Completed online courses and self-study in React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and related technologies.
- Worked on personal projects to apply and reinforce newly acquired skills.

Contract Frontend Developer

Sijal In Stiches LLP

April 2021 - March 2022

- Created user interfaces with Angular, TypeScript and HTML/CSS to ensure responsive design across platforms, improved web page performance by 25–50%.
- Implemented PrimeNG Angular UI component library to ensure more efficient usage of the codebase for better and faster development
- Created landing pages, dashboards for the ecommerce website.
- · Collaborated with backend developers to integrate frontend components with back-end APIs.
- Maintained strict budgetary and scheduling guidelines to satisfy customers with high-quality, targeted designs.

Test Engineer

Wipro Limited

November 2018 - November 2020, Bengaluru

- Developed and implemented comprehensive test automation framework, resulting in 20% decrease in test cycles and improved coverage to 60% from 40%.
- Executed various manual and automated tests, and tracked potential software problems via bug tracking system.
- Identified and tracked defects with Jira and supported developers in resolving problems by completing additional tests.
- · Collaborated with developers and product owners to stay current on product features and intended functionality.
- Created automation scripts using Parasoft SOA Test tool and Jython.
- Kept scripts and test cases updated with current requirements for future reference and use.

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Java

Frontend: React, Angular, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

Backend: MongoDB, NodeJS Others: Figma, Photoshop

PROJECTS

Plant Store Website - HTML, CSS

apooja.dev/plant-store-website/

- Designed this website frontend just for fun. It uses **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**.
- It also has Dark and Light theme support.

Todo List App - React

apooja.dev/todo-list-app/

- Worked on the project for the purpose of learning React.
- · Built using React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science & Engineering

Shri Ramswaroop Memorial University, Lucknow · 2014 - 2018 · GPA - 7.38